KANAK **TYAGI** SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Unv. Regd. No. - 1373910021 Mob - 9761107031

tyagiknk.india@gmail.com Bangalore



PROFILE

A young, passionate and professional React JS developer with 3+ years of experience in building high performant websites with reusable components. Have worked in fast paced startup environment. Have deep understanding of Reactis and Nextis



EXPERIENCE

Melorra

Software Engineer Oct 2020 - Present

Zwayam

Software Engineer March 2019 - Sept 2020 Here earlier the site was CSR so our team migrated the full code to SSR for better SEO and performance. I worked on increasing the site speed. Site link: https://www.melorra.com/

Being a software engineer here I have been working here in Reactjs developer in the front end, and nodejs developer in the backend.



EDUCATION

JRE Group Of Institutions Greater Noida

B.Tech In Computer Science & Engineering (2013-2017)

St. Mary's Convent School

Class 12th, CBSE



SKILLS

Reactjs, Nextjs, Redux, NPM, Axios, Context-API, Material-UI, Html, CSS, Bootstrap, ES6 Features, JavaScript, React-Hooks, RESTful, JSON, Firebase, Git.

TOOLS

Visual Studio Code, Windows OS, **JetBrains WebStorm**

Melorra

Melorra is a e-commerce website where gold jewellery is sold online. The site is Server Side Rendered using Nextjs for better Search Engine Optimization. Optimized the code using intersection observer so that the site can load up fast. Used Context-api for managing the app wise state. Used local Storage to keep data intact so that when user comes after visiting other pages its cart data, wishlist data is safe.

Technologies Used- Reactjs, Nextjs,Bootstrap,Context-API,Hooks **Link-** https://www.melorra.com/

Amazon-Clone (Open Source)

It's a web application which allows users to buy various products. User can register as a new user and can login at any time using his/her login credentials.

User can add various Items into the cart.

Technologies Used- React, Context-API, Hooks, Firebase, CSS, Material-Ui **Link-** https://clone-c3161.web.app

Facebook-Clone (Open Source)

It's a web application which allows to add post real time. User can register as a new user and can login at any time using his/her login credentials.

Technologies Used- React, Context-API, Hooks, Firebase, CSS, Material-Ui **Link-** https://facebook-clone-f4985.web.app

NetFlix-Clone (Open Source)

It's a web application where we are getting all the movies from themoviedb.org. And displaying it according to different categories.

Technologies Used- Axios, Context-API, Hooks, Firebase, CSS, Material-Ui **Link-** https://netflix-clone-d6537.web.app/



K ACHIEVEMENTS

Got **97 percentile** in Computer Science section of Amcat with grade A.

Got **74 percentile** in Computer programming section of Amcat with grade A.



SOCIAL PROFILES

Github - https://github.com/kanaktyagi **LinkedIn** - https://www.linkedin.com/in/kanak-tyagi-6949478b